GAURAV GARG

Leamington Spa, UK

Mobile EMAIL Skype LinkedIn

(+44)7878093988 gauravthailand@gmail.com gauravlabs https://www.linkedin.com/in/gauravlabs/

SUMMARY

An experienced game programmer with the ability to quickly pick up and use new program languages, tools and software applications. A dedicated team member with a passion for making video games as well as a patient and creative problem solver who is known for commitment to excellence and a track record of delivering work on schedule. I believe in continuously enhancing my skills and learning methods to improve my work and myself.

SKILLS

Excellent command over languages and tools such as **C# and Unity3d**Worked on several Game Engines such as **Unity3d**, **HGE**, **Irrlicht** and **Unreal Development kit**.
C++ / C, Objective-C, Web technologies, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, NodeJS, SQL, NoSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, React, Solidity, Blockchain. Advanced knowledge and experience with DirectX.

EXPERIENCE

PixelToys Games, (Senior Full Stack Developer) Leamington, United Kingdom (Feb/2022 – Current)

Panda - Responsible for managing the full stack development for application.

Integrate PvP Features like matchmaking, leaderboard on server side.

Integrate login system and tools on client side.

Outerdawn Games, (Lead Programmer) Auckland, New Zealand (Oct/2019 – Jan/2022)

Mana Monsters – Match 3 Battle System Game for iOS and Android using Unity Engine.

Integrating async PvP system, Leaderboards, Seasons.

Ensured Timely project completion, and maintained high quality standards.

Handling and managing project and programming teams and scrum.

Erawat Games, (Founder & Developer) India (August/2017 – Current)

Death Road – Top down shooter game for PC, Unity Engine.

Handling the entire Game Development process as Indie including Designing and Programming.

Casual Games – Worked on several casual games like TicTacToe Jungle, Love On Top, and other several client projects.

Loom Network & Arkavis Siam Co Ltd., (Lead Software Developer) Bangkok, Thailand (May/2016 – Aug/2019)

Relentless – Digital Collectible Card Game for PC, Mac, iOS and Android using Unity Engine.

Mentored junior developers and provided technical guidance

Collaborated with designers to create intuitive user interfaces

Conducted code reviews and ensured high-quality standards Developed scalable and maintainable code for various mobile platforms.

Implemented agile methodology to improve team efficiency

R.A.I.D - Robots and Incredible Dungeons – F2P Multiplayer Action RPG for iOS and Android in Unity.

B.O.B - **Boss of Bots** – F2P Multiplayer Platformer for iOS and Android in Unity.

Working on server logic and client side programming for both projects.

Maintenance of projects and code reviewing outsource partner code.

Integrate systems such as Character selection and Engine Upgrade.

Trained 8+ team members on Agile during this period.

Reliance Games, (Senior Game Engineer) Pune, India (Oct/2012 – Apr/2016)

Ironkill - Fighting Game for iOS and Android in Unity

Lead all aspects of programming

Managed project schedule and dependencies for integrating game assets.

Programmed Data Management modules, UI systems and integration.

Cloud saving system and integration for both iOS and Android using iCloud and GPGS.

Social, IAP, VGP's, AD networks Integrations.

MadHop – Arcade, Endless Runner Game for Android in Unity

Entire Game development, with Multiplayer Integration using Nextpeer.

Mob vs. Monster – Tower Defense Game in Unity.

Programmed Character control system and animation systems.

Waypoint Tool – system in unity suitable for Game designers and Game artists.

Rosetta Stone - Kids Lingo Word Builder - Unity3D

Reliance Games, (Game Programmer) Pune, India (Feb/2012 – Oct/2012)

RealSteel – Fighting Game for iOS and Android in Unity.

Responsible for weekly builds, milestones, updates and maintenance.

Dancing With the Stars – Music, Rhythm Game for iOS and Android in Unity.

Avatar Customisation Tool System using xml.

UI Flow Integration using EzGUI plugin.

Walnut Games, (Game Programmer) Kolkata, India (July/2010 – Jan/2012)

Psychopathic – Action Adventure Game for Web.(Unity3d)

I had the opportunity to work on multiple projects and gain valuable experience in the gaming industry. I was responsible for developing and implementing game mechanics, creating engaging gameplay experiences, and collaborating with the design team, responsible for Third person controller, Finite State Mechanism, Camera Controller, AI.

Other projects - Puzzle falls, Space Vader, SquishIt, Parachute Ring, Hit and Run Bandits, Joes Crab Shack.

EDUCATION

Indira Gandhi National University

Bachelor of Computer Applications (2004 - 2007)

Instructor on Udemy

Create First DApp Using Truffle and Ganache - Course Link

An article published on Mutli|Platform.com regarding "How I made a 2D-game in unity as indie" - Article Link

BOOK REVIEWER

Learning C# by Developing Games with Unity 3D Beginner's Guide - Available on Amazon store.